So then, have you made up
your mind to take the exam?
Of course! I can even wag my tail too if you'd like.
Very well.
From now on, you two will apply yourself to
your studies wherever you feel is most suitable.
"The Sewing Life Alchemist"?
Shou Tucker—
the foremost authority on transmuting living bodies.
And so, we came to spend the remaining time before our exam at the Tucker house.
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
Two years ago,
Mr. Tucker successfully transmuted
a Chimera that could speak man's language.
He has taken the State Alchemist Certification Examination as well.
A Chimera that speaks man's language?!
It was a composite beast that was created at the cost of multiple creatures that had differing genetics.
Or, to put it another way, a Chimera that could understand what a person says and could speak.
Awesome!
Mr. Tucker also lives with his daughter, who is about to turn four.
Then he doesn't have a wife?
Here we are.
Wow, it's huge!
Incredible, huh, Brother?
What are you doing?
Come over here, quickly!
Oh, right...
B-Brother?
You can't do that, you know, Alexander!
Oh, I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
You're Tucker-san?
Yeah, I'm terribly sorry about all this.
We don't have any woman's touch around here.
It's like this inside the house too.
Wow. Bigger Brother's clothes are funny.
Aren't they heavy?
It's all right.
Big Brother is very strong.
I'm sure you'll have a chance to
discuss their natures at some point.
Until you do, just accept them.
Okay, Nina, go play outside.
Alexander must be lonesome.
Okay then, I'll see you later.
Who would have thought you'd aspire to be State Alchemists at your ages?
If there's anything I can do for you,
just let me know, okay?
Well, Tucker-san, I'd like to have you
show us the Chimera you transmuted.
Me too.
Oh, it died not long after
it was transmuted, you see...
Anyways, passing marks come first.
It will take more than just an
overnight effort to pass this test.
This is the materials room. You're free to use it.
This is incredible, Brother.
It's full of books I've never even seen!
The materials in here are just a fraction
compared to what they have
at the National Central Library.
If you pass the test, you can get
materials that will give you dozens—
no, hundreds of times
more knowledge than this.
Is that right?
Brother, we should get busy—
Oh, Brother...
Ed-kun, are you making any progress with your studies?
Yeah, some.
But there's so much stuff here that I didn't know.
The test is hard even for adults who have received special education.
But you're still so young.
You don't need to force yourself to
worry about it this year.
No...
I'll try to do everything that I can,
no matter how slim the
possibilities are of me passing.
If I can keep moving ahead...
Bigger Brother,
you haven't eaten anything!
That won't do! You have to make sure to eat!
Huh? Um...
Thanks.
This sure does look delicious.
Be sure you chew it well!
Mm-hmm.
This sure is good!
Here! Have another one!
Can't sleep?
Yeah. My head is too full of all the things I learned.
Oh, yeah?
Say, Brother...
I'm sure you'll be able
to pass the test.
So you should at least get a good night's rest.
It sure takes me back, the way this all feels.
The two of us wanted nothing
but to become State Alchemists.
Once we did, we felt that some kind of path would become open to us.
Oh no, is it this late already?
Al, where are you?
Is he off playing?
Al!
Brother!
Little Big Brother, it snowed!
Big Brothers,
I wish you could stay here all the time
after you pass your test.
Big Brother, what are you drawing?
It's called a transmutation circle.
It's an incantation to get a wish granted.
All right!
Watch this!
Incredible! Big Brother,
that was amazing!
Not bad!
Major Hughes!
Hey there! I've come to pick you up.
It's your birthday today, right, Ed?
Now that you mention it...
How would you know
something like that?
I am with the research department, you know.
Come on, let's go to my house. My wife is waiting.
You too there, little lady.
A celebration is more fun
if you share it with everyone!
Come on in!
Thank you all for coming.
This is my wife, Gracia.
Your stomach's so big!
Oh, my goodness!
You're going to have a baby?
Very shortly now.
There's a big fuss inside my tummy saying "I want to come out soon!"
Really?
Do you want to feel?
N-No!
Nina wants to feel!
Go ahead, Nina-chan.
It moved!
Incredible! Incredible!
Okay then, does anyone want refills on their tea?
Oh, thanks!
Gracia!
Honey, uma—
Uma? [horse]
Umareru! [the baby's coming]
I-It can't be...!
The due date isn't here yet!
Well, the baby wants to come out already.
A doctor!
We have to get to a doctor!
Th-There's a blizzard!
In that case, I'll bring a doctor here!
Sit tight, Gracia!
J-Just a sec—
Sorry about this, everyone.
Gracia-san, I brought some hot water!
Thank you.
Set it there on the floor.
Wh-What else?
Let' see... I suppose
we'll need a lot of towels.
Towels, you say? All right!
The doctor sure is taking a long time.
Yeah, with all this snow...
I can't take any more! I'm dying!
Brother! Gracia-san said she's going to die!
Sh-She couldn't be...!
She's not dead, is she?
Mama-san!
You idiot! She's just lost consciousness, right?!
But if you think about it like alchemy,
there's a considerable cost in creating a new life!
Childbirth isn't alchemy, you know!
Th-Thank goodness she's alive! Are you all right, Gracia-san?
Dammit, what should we do?!
How can there be nothing
we can do at a time like this?!
Big Brother,
the water is cold.
Ah, okay.
Brother! What did you just do?
N-Nothing...
N-Nothing? But where's the transmutation circle?!
Then how did the water get hot?
How would I know?!
Must've been force of mind!
Here it comes!
What should we do?!
Isn't the doctor here yet?!
Outstanding! Outstanding, Gracia!
Thanks to everybody.
I'm really, really grateful.
W-We didn't do anything.
That's not true.
You stayed at my side.
This alchemy stuff—turns out it wasn't any help at all, huh?
In contrast, mothers are
something awesome, huh?
They can do something an alchemist wouldn't be able to do in a hundred years.
The same goes for our mother.
Al?
I wonder if I was that warm and soft when I was born.
O-Of course you were!
Really?
After that, we became
much more absorbed in alchemy.
It was all we could do, wishing to take back the bodies we were born with.
Come to think of it, Brother,
you heated that water before without using a transmutation circle, huh?
Yeah. That situation was something out of the ordinary, though.
Even so, it was still
incredible of you, Brother.
I'll have to keep at it too.
W-Well then, I'll quiz you.
The test was drawing ever nearer.
Every year, the test is held in the order of written exam, then interview, and then practical skills.
I can't say anything about
how many people will be taking it,
but each year, there are only one or two people who pass.
You mean, that's all?
Um, what kind of things do they do during the interview?
In my case, all they did was a question-and-answer session,
but I understand that there are also physical examinations, depending on the person.
A physical examination, huh?
And another thing...
At the practical skills test,
about half the people brought the results of their research, like I did,
and about half showed off
their transmuting on the spot.
What are you guys going to do?
I'm at a loss. What are we going
to do for the practical skills test?
What if they do a physical exam before then?
They'll find out that the inside of this armor is empty.
Hey, I'm sure that Lt. Col. Mustang is thinking up something for us.
I sure hope so.
As we embraced our uneasiness, the day of the test finally came.
We will now begin the
preliminary examination.
Begin!
Big Brothers! How did it go?
I didn't make it to the last question.
I got through all of it,
but next comes the interview.
I never would've expected the younger brother to pass the written too.
Is there a problem?
The interview...
You can't mean it!
I can't accept this!
Why? Why would you tell me
not to go through the interview?!
If you wish to go any further
while still concealing your past,
that's the only thing you can do.
But I want to stay together with my brother!
It's okay, Al.
It's like Old Lady Pinako said.
State Alchemists get rounded up
whenever war breaks out.
Sometimes they have to use
their alchemy to harm others
for the good of the people.
Passing equals "dog of the military."
But still!
It'll be enough for me alone
to become a State Alchemist.
I'll make sure I become one and grant you your wish.
Brother...
A golden three-legged stool?
Why doesn't it fall over like that?
Take a seat. If you are a true alchemist,
the chair will not refuse you.
Alchemist, at no time
allow yourself to be afraid!
Very well.
So then, let's hear your
motivations for taking the test.
I-It's because...
It's because...?
I made a promise!
I told the only other
member of my family
that I would make sure
I became a State Alchemist!
Al...
We chose the right path, didn't we?
I don't know. But the one thing
I am sure about...
is that I want to touch you once again, Brother.
It's strange, huh?
Here we are, always so near each other,
but I can't even remember
what it feels like to touch you,
or the warmth of your body.
And then, the morning
of the practical skills test...
I'm off.
Big Brother...
Nina...
Big Brother, here.
It's an incantation
to grant your wish!
Thanks, Nina!
We now offer you all of the matter that exists within these premises.
Please make use of it to
transmute whatever you like.
Whatever I like?
What on earth should I do in order to pass?
It is a magnificent article,
but the fact that he's used up all of his strength is, well...
Is he serious?!
I'll go next.
Trees and water?
I hope Big Brother is all right.
He has your incantation, Nina, so he'll be fine.
Nicely done.
He made paper and hydrogen
out of the wood and water, huh?
This isn't good!
So he can do it without a transmutation circle...
An underage alchemist, huh?
Intriguing.
Wow! How amazingly beautiful!
Al...
I'm going to stop all my wavering!
I'm going to just look straight ahead
and race forward!
If I dead-end, I'll cross that bridge when I come to it.
Someday, no matter what,
I'm going to return you
back to the way you were!
When you do, Brother,
your body will be there with me!
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 7: "Night of the Chimera's Cry"
Nina...